<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>College of Dance</name>
        <description>College of Dance Bard subclass (2024 Player’s Handbook)</description>
        <author>Custom Content</author>
        <update version="1.0">
            <file name="college_of_dance.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/owenmarty03/aurora-college-of-dance/main/college_of_dance.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <!-- Subclass Definition -->
    <element name="College of Dance" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="college-of-dance">
        <supports>Bard</supports>  <!-- Links this to the Bard class -->
        <description>
            <p>A Bard subclass focused on dance and movement.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>College of Dance features.</description>
        </sheet>
        
        <!-- Level 3 Features -->
        <element name="Dance Virtuoso" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="dance-virtuoso">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on any Charisma (Performance) check you make that involves dancing.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Advantage on dancing Performance checks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        
        <element name="Release Your Inhibitions" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="release-your-inhibitions">
            <description>
                <p>While you aren’t wearing armor or wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Unarmored AC: 10 + Dex + Cha.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        
        <element name="Agile Strikes" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="agile-strikes">
            <description>
                <p>When you spend a use of Bardic Inspiration as part of an action, bonus action, or reaction, you can make one unarmed strike as part of that same action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Unarmed strike with Bardic Inspiration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        
        <element name="Bardic Damage" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="bardic-damage">
            <description>
                <p>When you hit with an unarmed strike, you deal bludgeoning damage equal to one roll of your Bardic Inspiration die plus your Dexterity modifier instead of the normal damage. This doesn’t expend the Bardic Inspiration die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Enhanced unarmed strike damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        
        <!-- Level 6 Features -->
        <element name="Inspiring Movement" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="inspiring-movement">
            <description>
                <p>When an enemy you can see ends its turn within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction and expend a Bardic Inspiration die to move up to half your speed without provoking opportunity attacks. One ally of your choice within 30 feet then can also use their reaction to move up to half their speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Reaction movement for you and an ally.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        
        <element name="Tandem Footwork" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="tandem-footwork">
            <description>
                <p>When you roll initiative and aren’t incapacitated, you can expend a Bardic Inspiration die to grant yourself and each ally within 30 feet who can see or hear you a bonus to initiative equal to the number rolled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Initiative bonus for you and allies.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        
        <!-- Level 14 Features -->
        <element name="Leading Evasion" type="Class Feature" source="PHB 2024" id="leading-evasion">
            <description>
                <p>When you make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage on a success and only half damage on a failure, if you aren’t incapacitated. Additionally, when any creatures within 5 feet of you make the same saving throw, you can choose for them to gain this benefit as well.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Improved evasion for you and nearby creatures.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    </element>
</elements>
